Readme

Master repository link: https://markus.teach.cs.toronto.edu/git/csc207-2019-01/group_0357 
Cloning the repository
Begin by copying the master repository link above
Open up an existing or new intellij project
To open up the folder, click file → New → project from version control → Git → paste the repo link and open it up
Mark the file named group_0357 as sources root

Running the program
To  open up the class that contains the main method, click group_0357 → phase2 → Model
Run the class named Model

Interacting with the system
Upon being prompted to type in a key, do so. This will lead to other options to explore the ATM
The bank manager can view info summary and perform transaction on user, perform transfer such as depositing into accounts and transfer funds between accounts.
The User can log in or request to create new user, once has access to accounts, they can view info, perform transaction and request the creation of new accounts. The types of transactions they can perform is pay bill and deposit money into their accounts.
Options:
Logging in or creating an account
Bank Manager
To login to this account successfully, type in BMuser for the username and BMpass for the password
Login We decided to implement our main method in such a way that requires the Bank Manager to have a form of identification to access the ATM to keep access to funds in the ATM secure. 
Once the Bank Manager has been granted access, it is given 

User Login
		
Create a new account



Design justifications
Encapsulation
We defined an operator as someone who can interact with the ATM machine through an account
Encapsulation was one of the our main priorities. On a project structure level, we divided up our classes into packages that deal with certain functionalities. This helps with extending our project as someone working on our project could find classes and methods from a small group of classes that are related to what is being searched for
The transaction class in the FundTransfers package hides the way in which transactions are made from the account class.
The create new account method hides the way in which the user adds to its list of accounts because the bank manager gets and sets users
MVC
We loosely had the MVC pattern in mind due to the the fact that our program displays information to the user.
Classes such as user and bank manager have a mix of View and Controller
The class “Model” is mainly where we bridge the controller and view of our project, however, it has a bit of “view” implemented into it as it prints options to the screen for the user to choose from
Single Responsibility Principle
Our classes were designed and implemented in a way that deals with one main idea
Our transaction class deals deals with performing a transaction
Our ATM class can only perform things that alter the amount of bills that it has
Our accounts class holds, gets and sets information to do with its variables
The user class is everything to do with the user’s bank account
Project extensibility
Bank worker superclass - with phase 2 in mind, we created this super class in order for other forms of workers to be made easily. 
In bank manager, we defined an arraylist of bank managers to support the possibility of there being different bank managers
